<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-07-18T11:21:22-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/</id><title type="html">i.i</title><subtitle>Wow check out my cool website.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Discipline</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2017/07/17/Discipline.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Discipline" /><published>2017-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2017/07/17/Discipline</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2017/07/17/Discipline.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been almost a year now, a year since I’ve shifted my perspective. Shifted
my focus to that of being disciplined. Shifted my sight to that of the motion of
things rather than the end points. It was exercise I think.. or was it
Buddhism.. or was it both? Some kind of vector. It was pushing me. Pushing me
towards something. And I felt that. That push towards. When I let go of grasping
at an island far away, when I laid back to allow the winds of change to guide
me, that’s when I feel I found my true footing. It was in the act of doing. Of
picking up, of putting down, of resting, and repeating. That is where I found my
sanctuary. That is where I found my strength.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I put that guiding wind into all that I do. I have cultivated the
practice of exercise. I have cultivated the practice of journaling. And though I
can not say I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; cultivated the practice of meditation, it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; something I
actively cultivate. And that active cultivation is the key. I must cultivate the
practice of blogging. I must cultivate the practice of sharing my strength. I
must cultivate the practice of strengthing my cultivation. Of being disciplined
in self-discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am finding a love for the present progressive tense.&lt;br /&gt; 
I am finding a love for my body.&lt;br /&gt;
I am finding a love for my mind.&lt;br /&gt;
I am that which I am resonating with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it is my duty to be continuing the cultivation&lt;br /&gt;
of a resonating direction in tune with compassion,&lt;br /&gt;
as the fortitude of my mind and body depend on it.. and that of those of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aside, I think I’m going to update this category to “Life” intead of
“Notice”. Also, learning Unity has been going really well! I’ve been working on
a tool that will let me place things relative to the camera more easily. It’s
been a lot of fun to work on!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notice" /><summary type="html">It’s been almost a year now, a year since I’ve shifted my perspective. Shifted my focus to that of being disciplined. Shifted my sight to that of the motion of things rather than the end points. It was exercise I think.. or was it Buddhism.. or was it both? Some kind of vector. It was pushing me. Pushing me towards something. And I felt that. That push towards. When I let go of grasping at an island far away, when I laid back to allow the winds of change to guide me, that’s when I feel I found my true footing. It was in the act of doing. Of picking up, of putting down, of resting, and repeating. That is where I found my sanctuary. That is where I found my strength.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning Unity</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2017/07/03/Learning-Unity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Unity" /><published>2017-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2017/07/03/Learning-Unity</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2017/07/03/Learning-Unity.html">&lt;p&gt;So, I began last week, going through the Unity Adventure Tutorial video series.
Oh man, I think it was a mistake to put so much focus on the video part. They
were definitely informative, but man I just can &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; sit through them. It is
taking me wayyy longer than it reasonably should to finish just seven vidoes. So
I’ve re-assesed how &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; learn best, and have decided to just jump in, start
making a game, and start referencing that &lt;em&gt;sweet sweet&lt;/em&gt; documentation. It’s how I’ve
come to learn all the other concepts I found too difficult in the past, and
it’ll most certainly be the way I learn unity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, my drive for discipline has allowed me to push through 90% of the
content (and just for completion, I’m most definitely going to sit through that
          last 10%), so I’ve learned quite a bit about how Unity works and some
of the different tools it has built in. I’ve also been able to set it up with
git and git-lfs (for the binary assets) and got a vim-like setup working with
Visual Studio. So I feel supppper ready to start a new project on my own feet.
I’m not entirely sure what I will make, but I think I will start with a new
design of SoundBall and see what it develops to from there. Lately, I’ve been
concerned with the quality of Mobile Games. Psychologically addictive gameplay
seems to be present even in the ones of good quality. That’s so concerning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, I think the format of this blog may evolve over time, and I’m
eager to see how it turns out. Does something like this belong in notice?
Maybe I just need to find a better name for this category set. Hmmm, we will
see!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notice" /><summary type="html">So, I began last week, going through the Unity Adventure Tutorial video series. Oh man, I think it was a mistake to put so much focus on the video part. They were definitely informative, but man I just can not sit through them. It is taking me wayyy longer than it reasonably should to finish just seven vidoes. So I’ve re-assesed how I learn best, and have decided to just jump in, start making a game, and start referencing that sweet sweet documentation. It’s how I’ve come to learn all the other concepts I found too difficult in the past, and it’ll most certainly be the way I learn unity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SoundBall #003: Iteration 2 Complete</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/06/23/SoundBall-003.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SoundBall #003: Iteration 2 Complete" /><published>2017-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/06/23/SoundBall-003</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/06/23/SoundBall-003.html">&lt;p&gt;This week I’ve finished up the second iteration of this mindful
sound-piano-thing experiment. And now, for a post-mortem!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SoundBall003A.gif&quot; alt=&quot;SoundBall Second Iteration&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the technicals:&lt;br /&gt;
I’m not sure javascript was the right fit for me for prototyping.
It’s quick to develop, and quick to share, but only for the most straightforward
of ideas. There are also some latency issues, even though I’m not doing
anything particularly intensive. And that’s no good!
As I’m not actually concerned with the quick-sharing aspect, I’m planning on
making a switch over to unity.
I think both approaches have a bit of a learning curve before an acceptable
prototyping speed can be achieved, but unity promises far more, in terms of
testing more complex ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the design:&lt;br /&gt;
Although there is &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; substance in the current iteration, as a whole, the design is
currently unsuccesful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the exploration into heavyness, but the slipping part is unnessential to
this plaything’s purpose. Originally it was there as an ‘encouragement’ for the
player to drop the ball and see the frequencies collapse into a note, however in
practice, this slipping is frustrating, and since the center of the ball
determines the current playing frequency, it only serves to weaken the mindful
connection between sound and player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘encouragement’ has also been replaced by the starting state of the ball.
I imagine that the start screen for this game will have the ball hovering, and
on start the ball will fall and collapse down the first note. This will clearly
demonstrate what the main functionality of this plaything is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the intuition of the exponentially increasing frequency of each ascending
note is largely lost. The game is currently too much of a move this ball above
the line and drop kind of deal. It lacks an emphasis in the exploration needed
to imbue a mindful play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graphically, putting aside roughness due to being a prototype,
the gradients need to be expanded into something more visually meaningful.
Currrently, the compressed compression that they hold is visually lost. (Also, they are
somewhat incorrect, but that’s not as important as it can be patched up later.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also non obvious that the piano keys are pressable. It is most certainly
worth the effort to improve this. Changing the keys to be more piano-like could
solve this problem, as well as improve the connection between frequency and note
for the player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can play this version by clicking
&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.i.001.run/PlayfulMedia001/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
And view the source by clicking
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eyedoteye/PlayfulMedia001&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2017-06-27: I’ve made some usability updates based on initial feedback.
The rising pitch sound was completely inaudible so I’ve shifted the octave up
two and increased the sound volume. Also, I realized for some reason I was
starting the piano roll on a C note. The new piano roll starts on A4.&lt;br /&gt;
Previously the ball was unable to be picked up by the parts of it that were
underneath the first note line. This was a leftover from an earlier build were
that part of the ball was drawn over. This has been fixed.&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve even gone a step further and allowed the ball to take selection priority
so it can be picked up even if it’s underneath a piano key.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is why playtesting is super important!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These changes are more of a band-aid than a proper fix. Pure higher frequencies
tend to evoke an unpleasantness. In the future, I think pitch-shifting a
flavored tone would be preferable. (Maybe from a sound bowl?)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I will spend more time exploring heavyness as a separate project. It’s
pretty interesting!
But also, I will now spend time re-designing a bunch of things and
re-approaching this in Unity! It should serve as a good project for learning the
ropes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devlog" /><summary type="html">This week I’ve finished up the second iteration of this mindful sound-piano-thing experiment. And now, for a post-mortem!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SoundBall #002</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/06/18/SoundBall-002.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SoundBall #002" /><published>2017-06-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-06-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/06/18/SoundBall-002</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/06/18/SoundBall-002.html">&lt;p&gt;Getting the feel right between multiple input types and platforms is super
tricky business. .. I don’t even know if I’m covering all cases. I’ve decided I
hate webdev.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I’m having an anxious period. It seems I spend half the day re-centering
myself, and then I can spend the second half actually doing the cool things I
want to do. ;_;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most annoying part of anxiety is how much of your dedication it takes up.
Every now and then I’ll get this heavier bout’ of it, and I always think, ah yes, this
must be the last time, but alas it crawls back in just to remind me it’s
still there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not all bad. In a way, it’s a great force pushing me towards healthier habits..&lt;br /&gt;
In a way, it’s also super dummie. &amp;gt;:O&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all the nonsense, I’ve gotten a working prototype of heaviness!
It took a lot of rignamrooing, and I found taking a step back and really looking
at what I was doing helped me solve out some of the trickier bits.&lt;br /&gt;
I realized game systems don’t have to mimic reality!&lt;br /&gt;
I didn’t need to mimic how physics worked, I could make up my own rules and just
&lt;em&gt;emulate&lt;/em&gt; what I needed to!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SoundBall002A.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SoundBall Design Doc&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SoundBall002B.gif&quot; alt=&quot;SoundBall Second Iteration&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also re-added some basic audio. As a toy, it’s now actually starting to
become kind of fun!
There’s two interesting things about having the frequencies increase upwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I associate the ground with bassier frequencies, most likely because lower
frequencies travel very well through solids and start to become feeling just
as much as they are a sound.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When the ball drops, the frequency being played drops with it, mimicking the
falling whistle sound effect often used in creative media.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between learning unity, swedish, and keeping up with all my other new and
increasingly added routines, I think I’m burning out! I took some time to
reflect and have decided creating mandatory time for leisure and relaxation is a
good idea. (And not task oriented leisure like I have been tending to do!) 
So, I will not work on this project during the weekend. And I’ll try my best to
somehow manage all of these routines, maybe by cutting the expected load for
each day. I’ll see next week how that plays out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devlog" /><summary type="html">Getting the feel right between multiple input types and platforms is super tricky business. .. I don’t even know if I’m covering all cases. I’ve decided I hate webdev.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SoundBall #001</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/06/10/SoundBall-001.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SoundBall #001" /><published>2017-06-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-06-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/06/10/SoundBall-001</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/06/10/SoundBall-001.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m still thinking about the format for my posts on
the site, and how to find a balance between the commitment effort for each
category type. I think I want the articles to be even more fleshed out than they
are now, but I’d like the devlogs to be easier to just jot some thoughts into.
At the same time, I don’t want to leave without at least some interesting things
to give!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I’ve been working on some &lt;em&gt;Playful Media&lt;/em&gt; lately. Have been using javascript,
and boy oh boy are there some weird tradeoffs. Things are easier to get runing
on the screen, but the screen is wonky, and the latency is wonky, and the wonk
is wonky. BUT, I’ve been making some good progress with wrenching out all those
wonks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first iteration of the project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SoundBall001A.gif&quot; alt=&quot;SoundBall First Iteration&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gradient represents rising sound frequencies, and the ball is used to select
which one will currently be played through the speakers. The slider on the
bottom swaps between a linear view of the frequencies and a view that groups the
frequencies into constant pianokey widths (represented by the white lines).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I realized the current direction of things didn’t really feel
like it was teaching me about the relationship between frequencies and notes.
I wanted to create an experience that gave an intuitive and wordless
understanding! So, I pulled out some paper and began thinking about some actual
design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SoundBall001B.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SoundBall Design Doc&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Re-iterating was a breeze thanks to the understanding and helpful functions I
developed during the first exploration. However, still being new to canvas-dev,
I encountered a lot of resistance on getting it to work properly with
mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The touch was unresponsive, the canvas was offscreen, and even when I get
everything to work, the latency was cray!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all that, I had a lot of fun navigating through the challenges. And, I’m
back to a point where I can focus again on &lt;em&gt;how to make a virtual ball feel
heavy&lt;/em&gt;. A topic I’m really excited to write about later!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current iteration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SoundBall001C.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SoundBall Second Iteration&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m taking this weekend to do a little exploration into unity. Since latency is
so essential to gamefeel, I’m hoping I can get more performant prototypes
through their system instead…&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve actually been trying to do less code over the weekend and more reading,
mindfulness, etc, but that mental context switching is a skill still on its
training wheels!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m i.i,&lt;br /&gt;
and okay bye&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devlog" /><summary type="html">I’m still thinking about the format for my posts on the site, and how to find a balance between the commitment effort for each category type. I think I want the articles to be even more fleshed out than they are now, but I’d like the devlogs to be easier to just jot some thoughts into. At the same time, I don’t want to leave without at least some interesting things to give!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I Am Now A Poor Boy</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2017/06/03/I-Am-Now-A-Poor-Boy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Am Now A Poor Boy" /><published>2017-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2017/06/03/I-Am-Now-A-Poor-Boy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2017/06/03/I-Am-Now-A-Poor-Boy.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shanananaleedledeedledeedydeedledeedledum~&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SphereKoan IS ON PERMANENT HOLD!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve come to realize that my funds are simply too scarce for me to continue SphereKoan’s development,
, and have been spending the past week redirecting my efforts towards
getting a job! And not a dummy, snore-snore job, but a &lt;em&gt;cool&lt;/em&gt; job! And so I’ve
been trying to produce more regular content via simpler methods such as
javascript (and later, unity)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, also! I’ve sucessfully migrated the textual parts of my blog to this shiny new
home! Tumblr was proving to be quite finicky with longer text posts. And now
that I’ve gotten used to jeckyll, I see that there are a bunch of cool things I
can now do, that I couldn’t ever before! Horizons expanded!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And do not fret over the hold on SphereKoan, I am sure I will get back to it
once my situation is in a more stable state. I really liked the idea and the engine
I was building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With every down there is always a new potential upward!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notice" /><category term="informative" /><category term="delay" /><summary type="html">Shanananaleedledeedledeedydeedledeedledum~</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SphereKoan #003</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/23/SphereKoan-003.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SphereKoan #003" /><published>2017-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/23/SphereKoan-003</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/23/SphereKoan-003.html">&lt;p&gt;Good gosh, so much has occured since my last log two weeks ago. Both in my
personal and academic lives.&lt;br /&gt;
There was some period of some great turmoil, that I think really brought forth
the preceding explorations. I suppose there is always a flower to bloom in the
darkness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so due to those complications, I think I’m going to unguiltily give myself
an extra week to complete my #thatgamefeel challenge. I think that wil be a more
useful measure, to me, of where I currently am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, not all news is bleak!&lt;br /&gt;
I feel it’s rather important to remain disciplined in growth, despite the
adversities and challenges in life. So I’ve planted a couple new roots within my
being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve been deligently goiny through a demystifying mindfulness course
from coursera. I’ve even gotten accepted for a teensy-tiny scholarshiparuno! The
course has been really amazing so far. There is a lot of writing involved, and
that’s pretty tiring, so I’ve really been getting a chance to excercise that
discipline.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve also begun illustrating, and have even started venturing into digital
painting. It’s really fun and the act, in itself, is really encouraging.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good gosh, cold showers! After getting over the initial inhibitions, they
are actually &lt;em&gt;super amazing&lt;/em&gt;! Lately I’ve been starting the shower warm,
and then slowly transitioning into cold. That way I get to experience the
best of both worlds, it starts as relieving and then it leaves me with a
great feeeling of refreshment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oh, also! I’ve completely reorganized my room. It is now a low bed and
standing desk room. I’ve always believed that the room is a reflection of
the mind and vice-versa; so I’m really happy with this new setup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the SphereKoan front, there &lt;em&gt;has been&lt;/em&gt; some developments.
Notably, I am currently transitioning and updating my workflow to better
utilize YouCompleteMe. It’s a little tricky because I’m compiling windows
programs, but I’m developing the linux subsystem. I’ve also been making good
progress on piecing together the architecture. I’ve been pulling pieces of
my old projects together and reworking it to an infrastructure better suited
for 3D-interactive projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the technical boring stuff, I’ve also attached one of my
behind-the-scenes, rougher design notes below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SphereKoan003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SphereKoan Design Doc&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m i.i,&lt;br /&gt;
and okay bye&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devlog" /><category term="challenge" /><category term="delay" /><summary type="html">Good gosh, so much has occured since my last log two weeks ago. Both in my personal and academic lives. There was some period of some great turmoil, that I think really brought forth the preceding explorations. I suppose there is always a flower to bloom in the darkness.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Guides,</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/23/On-Guides.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Guides," /><published>2017-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/23/On-Guides</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/23/On-Guides.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about.. my childhood lately; about what I would say to him,
if I could reach back in time. &lt;br /&gt;
I’ve been thinking about what he would say to me. How would he see me? &lt;br /&gt;
Would he be proud? Confused? ..Upset? &lt;br /&gt;
What would he think about the things I had to say? &lt;br /&gt;
What &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; I have to say? &lt;br /&gt;
And what of my role in the future, as a parent to my child? &lt;br /&gt;
And what of my role in the present, as a parent to myself? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The parent is not only a gaurdian, but a guide to the child, to greater
fields, to greater heights.&lt;br /&gt;
..but who guides me..?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I thought about that for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-guides-and-how-do-they-differ-from-role-models-and-inspirations&quot;&gt;What are guides, and how do they differ from role-models and inspirations?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guides are those you trust to offer good direction. And they often
&lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be role-models, and they often &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be inspirations, or at
least, sources of. But unlike, role-models, and inspirations, guides are not
so essential to the core of your identity. Guides exist within a segment of
time; guides are temporary. They are those who help you build your path in the
present moment, and they last only until it is natural for your paths to
diverge. They are the architects whom advise you on segments of your journey,
but not the journey itself. And yet, through walking the guide-built path you
may find yourself in a similar direction as the guides, but that is not the
focus of the guide, that is just a possible effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-are-guides-important&quot;&gt;Why are guides important?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guides bring forth an awareness to our journey that is temporaly more
significant to us in the present. Often, it is difficult for us assess the
situations that are thrust upon us, and how we must navigate them in order to
truly further our goals. And we are naturally inclined to compare, but often
to weak frames of reference. The painter has little use in the rigurous
analysis of their path in relation to the path of their friend, the
accountant, or to the path of their idol, a historical and/or private figure
(both of which have very little insight to give); yet we do these things
anyways. And it causes a great split: between our identity, what we
&lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; we should be doing, and what we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; doing.&lt;br /&gt;
It is paramount to keep those things aligned. And we can begin through the
recognition of our guides in &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; present moment. Who &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; we look
to? Not just the figures we think about now and again, and are inspired by
their tenacity or vision, but who are we looking at &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt; for
insight?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-so-who-are-my-guides&quot;&gt;And so, who are &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; guides?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was actually a pretty fun mental model to explore. As I was exploring
this idea. I came to realize, I was actually very unclear as to who my current
guides are. And it took me a bit of time to really get that list together, but
now that I have, I certainly feel a greater sense of awareness; &lt;em&gt;and that
feels good!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Note: before we continue, there are some &lt;em&gt;kinda&lt;/em&gt; spoilery notes
about The Witness coming up, so please consider tuning out if you haven’t yet
gotten the chance to play this amazing game.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;jonathan-blow&quot;&gt;Jonathan Blow&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was March 26, 2016 at roughly 12:48pm PDT that Mr.Blow first planted a
magic seed into my noggin. Now this all occured, during a particularly
difficult period in my life. And I thought, from the little bits of The
Witness hype I overheard, that maybe, &lt;em&gt;maybe,&lt;/em&gt; the puzzles in this game
can help me regrow some clarity, in my otherwise decayed status.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I did not realize at the time, that The Witness was a game that secretly
brought the player forth into states of mindfulness. Almost &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt;
what I needed in a game at that moment. And most peculiarly, this was also a
time when in a &lt;em&gt;completely different effort&lt;/em&gt; I had picked up a book on
The Buddha’s first teachings; completely coincidental, yet, so incredibly
serendipitous. It really kind of added an extra layer to the whole
experience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And I remember reading something from Jonathan at one point, when he said
something to the affect of, “Don’t let &lt;em&gt;pundits&lt;/em&gt; define for you, what a
game should be”. And as I played The Witness, and as I discovered the..&lt;em&gt;kind
of amazing moments that are in the game,&lt;/em&gt; that idea of letting go of
popular preconceptions, pulled itself out of the ether of my memories,
directly into the center of my being, and &lt;em&gt;resonated&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;frankesmileshow&quot;&gt;FrankeSmileShow&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been following Francis Coloumbe’s work since I was &lt;em&gt;twelve&lt;/em&gt;.
Seeing him transform and grow, has been an amazing and incredibly encouraging
experience. When I first experienced Frankie, it was through Sluggy’s
Adventure, a game &lt;em&gt;so rudimentary&lt;/em&gt; in design and art-direction, that
looking back now, I’m sure even he kind of chuckles at how rough his start
was; and not in a way the he’s ashamed, but in a way that he is proud. Because
now? Frankie is this.. &lt;em&gt;part machine, part sanctuary&lt;/em&gt; of game and art,
energy. The pace and consistency at which he produces these incredible pieces
of art, animation, and prototypes is aboslutley astounding. And it’s not just
that he unstoppably churns at his passions, it’s that he does it with the most
humble and casual of demeanors. &lt;em&gt;yeah, idk arts just happen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;william-chyr&quot;&gt;William Chyr&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;William first entered my cognizance during my batch at the Recurse Center,
where after taking up a peer’s offer for a massage in exchange for cool-facts,
she informed me of her baloonman-turned-game-developer-friend. Now of course,
the whole situation was strange enough that I was sufficently intriguied. And
that’s when I discovered, this game that has been on my radar for a while,
Manifold Garden, was being developed by this very same man. And I was
astounded that I had any connection at all to the developer of such an
interesting and wonderous title. More importantly, I discovered &lt;em&gt;his
stream&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;William is a man whom, through doubts both self and familial, and stress both
creative and temporal, continually manages to find the drive and raw willpower
to continue ever onward, climbing up that mountain of passion. And all the
while, he carries with him a most sinscere cordiality. William is phenomenal.
It is &lt;em&gt;sooo~&lt;/em&gt; refreshing to see someone actively not only encouraging,
but embodying positive health within the creative stratosphere – a place
often plagued by the romanticization of poor health and balance. It was
William Chyr that got me thinking more actively about my diet, and I’m pretty
sure it was he whom &lt;em&gt;really helped&lt;/em&gt; seed my fervor for health in
creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lavhorre&quot;&gt;Lavhorre&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably the most recent and temporarly fluid of influences, Brittany
Salzone brings with her this most playful &lt;em&gt;yet focused&lt;/em&gt; attitude to her
process. Through her stream I grew the courage to try my hand at illustration.
But not just illustration, but the attitude and attenion I bring to it. It was
here that I began taking higher education in a creative field more seriously,
and it was here that I began to first question the shame I had been carrying
for so long about my creative passion. And with my questions came a
liberation; a freedom.&lt;br /&gt;
The strangest circumstances bring forth the most incredible of reflections. I
am very thankful to Lavhorre for enabling me in that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’m very thankful to &lt;em&gt;all of the guides&lt;/em&gt; in this list, for
enabling, and continuing to enable, my path.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="self-help" /><summary type="html">I’ve been thinking about.. my childhood lately; about what I would say to him, if I could reach back in time. I’ve been thinking about what he would say to me. How would he see me? Would he be proud? Confused? ..Upset? What would he think about the things I had to say? What do I have to say? And what of my role in the future, as a parent to my child? And what of my role in the present, as a parent to myself? The parent is not only a gaurdian, but a guide to the child, to greater fields, to greater heights. ..but who guides me..?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">So, Let’s Talk About Mental Health</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/15/So-Lets-Talk-About-Mental-Health.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="So, Let's Talk About Mental Health" /><published>2017-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/15/So-Lets-Talk-About-Mental-Health</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/15/So-Lets-Talk-About-Mental-Health.html">&lt;p&gt;For those that know me more personally, they know I’ve struggled with some
pretty bad juju when it comes to mental health. And it wasn’t without a strong
will, extensive therapy, medicine, and the support of some &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; great
people that I’ve been able to recover and transform my life into a positive
direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said, &lt;strong&gt;I &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; do not understand mental health. I do
not understand my condition; I &lt;em&gt;do not&lt;/em&gt; understand the symptoms; I do not
understand my treatment.&lt;/strong&gt; What I do understand, is that I was given a
choice. I was given the choice to let my deteriorated mind be something that
consumes me, something that degrades me, something that takes away my autonomy
and controls me; or,&lt;br /&gt;
I could let it be something I lean against, and push off. I could establish
&lt;em&gt;a relationship&lt;/em&gt; with this entity. I could soar. Because like it or
not,&lt;br /&gt;
I am entwined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I can choose, to push that aside, ignore it as a part of me that isn’t me; I
can say that it’s not so real, and that one day it will dissapear and bother me
no more &lt;em&gt;–but–&lt;/em&gt; but to say that is to deny myself &lt;em&gt;in the
moment&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
Because that’s what you have when you have an unfamiliar mind. You have methods
of molding the moment. Of molding your perception. Of &lt;em&gt;dealing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that doesn’t mean I’m advocating leaping off reality to soar in the
otherworld. &lt;br /&gt;
In fact, I’m advocating the opposite. I’m advocating the reflection with your
illness, that brings you forth to grounded feet. So rooted more in what it means
to be human, that the supposed nonsufferers look to you in awe, in how a tree
that extends &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; far above the clouds can remain so stable. And as they
reach to enjoy the passions in your fruit, you unfurl your branch, and you
whisper to them your secret:&lt;br /&gt;
“When I fell, I grew &lt;em&gt;twice&lt;/em&gt; as hard.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="mental-health" /><category term="inspiration" /><summary type="html">For those that know me more personally, they know I’ve struggled with some pretty bad juju when it comes to mental health. And it wasn’t without a strong will, extensive therapy, medicine, and the support of some really great people that I’ve been able to recover and transform my life into a positive direction.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SphereKoan #002</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/09/SphereKoan-002.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SphereKoan #002" /><published>2017-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/09/SphereKoan-002</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/09/SphereKoan-002.html">&lt;p&gt;I spent most of the week rummaging through cpp-con talks and handmade hero
videos for superior ways of approaching game programming. Games tend to work
best with: Production usage code first, fast failing, and compilation time type
checking. However, I think there are pieces and lessons from test-driven
development and contract-driven development that can be leveraged for a superior
overall dev experience. I may elaborate on them at a later time, as I haven’t
truly been able to test my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the notes I’ve taken since last week are repetitive and
half-thoughts. That’s just kind of part of the process. I’ve included here two
of the more refined pages I’ve managed to collect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SphereKoan002A.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SphereKoan Design Doc&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the Moments &amp;amp; Systems outline. When I first started writing this out,
I honestly had no idea what I was doing, just that I was doing it neatly, and
that somehow made me feel like I was doing something right. Pro strats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SphereKoan002B.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SphereKoan Design Doc&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I’m starting to delve in and really explore the controls. Having to
write them down like this helped me identify a couple problem areas that I
didn’t really see when I first started. I think an important thing to note is
that during this process I’m also being very mindful of how the 3D controls
relate to the 2D controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on that note, I’ve started taking a mindfulness course from coursera!
In addition to improving my daily life, I think it will be very useful once I
get to the iterative aspect of game design (Also, I strongly believe that positive health in creative fields needs to be discussed and encouraged much much more, but that’s a topic for another day).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m i.i,&lt;br /&gt;
and okay bye&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devlog" /><category term="challenge" /><summary type="html">I spent most of the week rummaging through cpp-con talks and handmade hero videos for superior ways of approaching game programming. Games tend to work best with: Production usage code first, fast failing, and compilation time type checking. However, I think there are pieces and lessons from test-driven development and contract-driven development that can be leveraged for a superior overall dev experience. I may elaborate on them at a later time, as I haven’t truly been able to test my thoughts.</summary></entry></feed>