<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-06-06T20:55:59-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/</id><title type="html">i.i</title><subtitle>Wow check out my cool website.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">I Am Now A Poor Boy</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2017/06/03/I-Am-Now-A-Poor-Boy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Am Now A Poor Boy" /><published>2017-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2017/06/03/I-Am-Now-A-Poor-Boy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2017/06/03/I-Am-Now-A-Poor-Boy.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shanananaleedledeedledeedydeedledeedledum~&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SphereKoan IS ON PERMANENT HOLD!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve come to realize that my funds are simply too scarce for me to continue SphereKoan’s development,
, and have been spending the past week redirecting my efforts towards
getting a job! And not a dummy, snore-snore job, but a &lt;em&gt;cool&lt;/em&gt; job! And so I’ve
been trying to produce more regular content via simpler methods such as
javascript (and later, unity)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, also! I’ve sucessfully migrated the textual parts of my blog to this shiny new
home! Tumblr was proving to be quite finicky with longer text posts. And now
that I’ve gotten used to jeckyll, I see that there are a bunch of cool things I
can now do, that I couldn’t ever before! Horizons expanded!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And do not fret over the hold on SphereKoan, I am sure I will get back to it
once my situation is in a more stable state. I really liked the idea and the engine
I was building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With every down there is always a new potential upward!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notice" /><category term="informative" /><category term="delay" /><summary type="html">Shanananaleedledeedledeedydeedledeedledum~</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SphereKoan #003</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/23/SphereKoan-003.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SphereKoan #003" /><published>2017-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/23/SphereKoan-003</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/23/SphereKoan-003.html">&lt;p&gt;Good gosh, so much has occured since my last log two weeks ago. Both in my
personal and academic lives.&lt;br /&gt;
There was some period of some great turmoil, that I think really brought forth
the preceding explorations. I suppose there is always a flower to bloom in the
darkness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so due to those complications, I think I’m going to unguiltily give myself
an extra week to complete my #thatgamefeel challenge. I think that wil be a more
useful measure, to me, of where I currently am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, not all news is bleak!&lt;br /&gt;
I feel it’s rather important to remain disciplined in growth, despite the
adversities and challenges in life. So I’ve planted a couple new roots within my
being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve been deligently goiny through a demystifying mindfulness course
from coursera. I’ve even gotten accepted for a teensy-tiny scholarshiparuno! The
course has been really amazing so far. There is a lot of writing involved, and
that’s pretty tiring, so I’ve really been getting a chance to excercise that
discipline.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve also begun illustrating, and have even started venturing into digital
painting. It’s really fun and the act, in itself, is really encouraging.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good gosh, cold showers! After getting over the initial inhibitions, they
are actually &lt;em&gt;super amazing&lt;/em&gt;! Lately I’ve been starting the shower warm,
and then slowly transitioning into cold. That way I get to experience the
best of both worlds, it starts as relieving and then it leaves me with a
great feeeling of refreshment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oh, also! I’ve completely reorganized my room. It is now a low bed and
standing desk room. I’ve always believed that the room is a reflection of
the mind and vice-versa; so I’m really happy with this new setup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the SphereKoan front, there &lt;em&gt;has been&lt;/em&gt; some developments.
Notably, I am currently transitioning and updating my workflow to better
utilize YouCompleteMe. It’s a little tricky because I’m compiling windows
programs, but I’m developing the linux subsystem. I’ve also been making good
progress on piecing together the architecture. I’ve been pulling pieces of
my old projects together and reworking it to an infrastructure better suited
for 3D-interactive projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the technical boring stuff, I’ve also attached one of my
behind-the-scenes, rougher design notes below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SphereKoan003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SphereKoan Design Doc&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m i.i,&lt;br /&gt;
and okay bye&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devlog" /><category term="challenge" /><category term="delay" /><summary type="html">Good gosh, so much has occured since my last log two weeks ago. Both in my personal and academic lives. There was some period of some great turmoil, that I think really brought forth the preceding explorations. I suppose there is always a flower to bloom in the darkness.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Guides,</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/23/On-Guides.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Guides," /><published>2017-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/23/On-Guides</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/23/On-Guides.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about.. my childhood lately; about what I would say to him,
if I could reach back in time. &lt;br /&gt;
I’ve been thinking about what he would say to me. How would he see me? &lt;br /&gt;
Would he be proud? Confused? ..Upset? &lt;br /&gt;
What would he think about the things I had to say? &lt;br /&gt;
What &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; I have to say? &lt;br /&gt;
And what of my role in the future, as a parent to my child? &lt;br /&gt;
And what of my role in the present, as a parent to myself? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The parent is not only a gaurdian, but a guide to the child, to greater
fields, to greater heights.&lt;br /&gt;
..but who guides me..?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I thought about that for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-guides-and-how-do-they-differ-from-role-models-and-inspirations&quot;&gt;What are guides, and how do they differ from role-models and inspirations?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guides are those you trust to offer good direction. And they often
&lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be role-models, and they often &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be inspirations, or at
least, sources of. But unlike, role-models, and inspirations, guides are not
so essential to the core of your identity. Guides exist within a segment of
time; guides are temporary. They are those who help you build your path in the
present moment, and they last only until it is natural for your paths to
diverge. They are the architects whom advise you on segments of your journey,
but not the journey itself. And yet, through walking the guide-built path you
may find yourself in a similar direction as the guides, but that is not the
focus of the guide, that is just a possible effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-are-guides-important&quot;&gt;Why are guides important?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guides bring forth an awareness to our journey that is temporaly more
significant to us in the present. Often, it is difficult for us assess the
situations that are thrust upon us, and how we must navigate them in order to
truly further our goals. And we are naturally inclined to compare, but often
to weak frames of reference. The painter has little use in the rigurous
analysis of their path in relation to the path of their friend, the
accountant, or to the path of their idol, a historical and/or private figure
(both of which have very little insight to give); yet we do these things
anyways. And it causes a great split: between our identity, what we
&lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; we should be doing, and what we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; doing.&lt;br /&gt;
It is paramount to keep those things aligned. And we can begin through the
recognition of our guides in &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; present moment. Who &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; we look
to? Not just the figures we think about now and again, and are inspired by
their tenacity or vision, but who are we looking at &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt; for
insight?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-so-who-are-my-guides&quot;&gt;And so, who are &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; guides?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was actually a pretty fun mental model to explore. As I was exploring
this idea. I came to realize, I was actually very unclear as to who my current
guides are. And it took me a bit of time to really get that list together, but
now that I have, I certainly feel a greater sense of awareness; &lt;em&gt;and that
feels good!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Note: before we continue, there are some &lt;em&gt;kinda&lt;/em&gt; spoilery notes
about The Witness coming up, so please consider tuning out if you haven’t yet
gotten the chance to play this amazing game.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;jonathan-blow&quot;&gt;Jonathan Blow&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was March 26, 2016 at roughly 12:48pm PDT that Mr.Blow first planted a
magic seed into my noggin. Now this all occured, during a particularly
difficult period in my life. And I thought, from the little bits of The
Witness hype I overheard, that maybe, &lt;em&gt;maybe,&lt;/em&gt; the puzzles in this game
can help me regrow some clarity, in my otherwise decayed status.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I did not realize at the time, that The Witness was a game that secretly
brought the player forth into states of mindfulness. Almost &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt;
what I needed in a game at that moment. And most peculiarly, this was also a
time when in a &lt;em&gt;completely different effort&lt;/em&gt; I had picked up a book on
The Buddha’s first teachings; completely coincidental, yet, so incredibly
serendipitous. It really kind of added an extra layer to the whole
experience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And I remember reading something from Jonathan at one point, when he said
something to the affect of, “Don’t let &lt;em&gt;pundits&lt;/em&gt; define for you, what a
game should be”. And as I played The Witness, and as I discovered the..&lt;em&gt;kind
of amazing moments that are in the game,&lt;/em&gt; that idea of letting go of
popular preconceptions, pulled itself out of the ether of my memories,
directly into the center of my being, and &lt;em&gt;resonated&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;frankesmileshow&quot;&gt;FrankeSmileShow&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been following Francis Coloumbe’s work since I was &lt;em&gt;twelve&lt;/em&gt;.
Seeing him transform and grow, has been an amazing and incredibly encouraging
experience. When I first experienced Frankie, it was through Sluggy’s
Adventure, a game &lt;em&gt;so rudimentary&lt;/em&gt; in design and art-direction, that
looking back now, I’m sure even he kind of chuckles at how rough his start
was; and not in a way the he’s ashamed, but in a way that he is proud. Because
now? Frankie is this.. &lt;em&gt;part machine, part sanctuary&lt;/em&gt; of game and art,
energy. The pace and consistency at which he produces these incredible pieces
of art, animation, and prototypes is aboslutley astounding. And it’s not just
that he unstoppably churns at his passions, it’s that he does it with the most
humble and casual of demeanors. &lt;em&gt;yeah, idk arts just happen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;william-chyr&quot;&gt;William Chyr&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;William first entered my cognizance during my batch at the Recurse Center,
where after taking up a peer’s offer for a massage in exchange for cool-facts,
she informed me of her baloonman-turned-game-developer-friend. Now of course,
the whole situation was strange enough that I was sufficently intriguied. And
that’s when I discovered, this game that has been on my radar for a while,
Manifold Garden, was being developed by this very same man. And I was
astounded that I had any connection at all to the developer of such an
interesting and wonderous title. More importantly, I discovered &lt;em&gt;his
stream&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;William is a man whom, through doubts both self and familial, and stress both
creative and temporal, continually manages to find the drive and raw willpower
to continue ever onward, climbing up that mountain of passion. And all the
while, he carries with him a most sinscere cordiality. William is phenomenal.
It is &lt;em&gt;sooo~&lt;/em&gt; refreshing to see someone actively not only encouraging,
but embodying positive health within the creative stratosphere – a place
often plagued by the romanticization of poor health and balance. It was
William Chyr that got me thinking more actively about my diet, and I’m pretty
sure it was he whom &lt;em&gt;really helped&lt;/em&gt; seed my fervor for health in
creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lavhorre&quot;&gt;Lavhorre&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably the most recent and temporarly fluid of influences, Brittany
Salzone brings with her this most playful &lt;em&gt;yet focused&lt;/em&gt; attitude to her
process. Through her stream I grew the courage to try my hand at illustration.
But not just illustration, but the attitude and attenion I bring to it. It was
here that I began taking higher education in a creative field more seriously,
and it was here that I began to first question the shame I had been carrying
for so long about my creative passion. And with my questions came a
liberation; a freedom.&lt;br /&gt;
The strangest circumstances bring forth the most incredible of reflections. I
am very thankful to Lavhorre for enabling me in that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’m very thankful to &lt;em&gt;all of the guides&lt;/em&gt; in this list, for
enabling, and continuing to enable, my path.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="self-help" /><summary type="html">I’ve been thinking about.. my childhood lately; about what I would say to him, if I could reach back in time. I’ve been thinking about what he would say to me. How would he see me? Would he be proud? Confused? ..Upset? What would he think about the things I had to say? What do I have to say? And what of my role in the future, as a parent to my child? And what of my role in the present, as a parent to myself? The parent is not only a gaurdian, but a guide to the child, to greater fields, to greater heights. ..but who guides me..?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">So, Let’s Talk About Mental Health</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/15/So-Lets-Talk-About-Mental-Health.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="So, Let's Talk About Mental Health" /><published>2017-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/15/So-Lets-Talk-About-Mental-Health</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/15/So-Lets-Talk-About-Mental-Health.html">&lt;p&gt;For those that know me more personally, they know I’ve struggled with some
pretty bad juju when it comes to mental health. And it wasn’t without a strong
will, extensive therapy, medicine, and the support of some &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; great
people that I’ve been able to recover and transform my life into a positive
direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said, &lt;strong&gt;I &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; do not understand mental health. I do
not understand my condition; I &lt;em&gt;do not&lt;/em&gt; understand the symptoms; I do not
understand my treatment.&lt;/strong&gt; What I do understand, is that I was given a
choice. I was given the choice to let my deteriorated mind be something that
consumes me, something that degrades me, something that takes away my autonomy
and controls me; or,&lt;br /&gt;
I could let it be something I lean against, and push off. I could establish
&lt;em&gt;a relationship&lt;/em&gt; with this entity. I could soar. Because like it or
not,&lt;br /&gt;
I am entwined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I can choose, to push that aside, ignore it as a part of me that isn’t me; I
can say that it’s not so real, and that one day it will dissapear and bother me
no more &lt;em&gt;–but–&lt;/em&gt; but to say that is to deny myself &lt;em&gt;in the
moment&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
Because that’s what you have when you have an unfamiliar mind. You have methods
of molding the moment. Of molding your perception. Of &lt;em&gt;dealing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that doesn’t mean I’m advocating leaping off reality to soar in the
otherworld. &lt;br /&gt;
In fact, I’m advocating the opposite. I’m advocating the reflection with your
illness, that brings you forth to grounded feet. So rooted more in what it means
to be human, that the supposed nonsufferers look to you in awe, in how a tree
that extends &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; far above the clouds can remain so stable. And as they
reach to enjoy the passions in your fruit, you unfurl your branch, and you
whisper to them your secret:&lt;br /&gt;
“When I fell, I grew &lt;em&gt;twice&lt;/em&gt; as hard.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="mental-health" /><category term="inspiration" /><summary type="html">For those that know me more personally, they know I’ve struggled with some pretty bad juju when it comes to mental health. And it wasn’t without a strong will, extensive therapy, medicine, and the support of some really great people that I’ve been able to recover and transform my life into a positive direction.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SphereKoan #002</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/09/SphereKoan-002.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SphereKoan #002" /><published>2017-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/09/SphereKoan-002</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/09/SphereKoan-002.html">&lt;p&gt;I spent most of the week rummaging through cpp-con talks and handmade hero
videos for superior ways of approaching game programming. Games tend to work
best with: Production usage code first, fast failing, and compilation time type
checking. However, I think there are pieces and lessons from test-driven
development and contract-driven development that can be leveraged for a superior
overall dev experience. I may elaborate on them at a later time, as I haven’t
truly been able to test my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the notes I’ve taken since last week are repetitive and
half-thoughts. That’s just kind of part of the process. I’ve included here two
of the more refined pages I’ve managed to collect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SphereKoan002A.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SphereKoan Design Doc&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the Moments &amp;amp; Systems outline. When I first started writing this out,
I honestly had no idea what I was doing, just that I was doing it neatly, and
that somehow made me feel like I was doing something right. Pro strats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SphereKoan002B.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SphereKoan Design Doc&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I’m starting to delve in and really explore the controls. Having to
write them down like this helped me identify a couple problem areas that I
didn’t really see when I first started. I think an important thing to note is
that during this process I’m also being very mindful of how the 3D controls
relate to the 2D controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on that note, I’ve started taking a mindfulness course from coursera!
In addition to improving my daily life, I think it will be very useful once I
get to the iterative aspect of game design (Also, I strongly believe that positive health in creative fields needs to be discussed and encouraged much much more, but that’s a topic for another day).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m i.i,&lt;br /&gt;
and okay bye&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devlog" /><category term="challenge" /><summary type="html">I spent most of the week rummaging through cpp-con talks and handmade hero videos for superior ways of approaching game programming. Games tend to work best with: Production usage code first, fast failing, and compilation time type checking. However, I think there are pieces and lessons from test-driven development and contract-driven development that can be leveraged for a superior overall dev experience. I may elaborate on them at a later time, as I haven’t truly been able to test my thoughts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Games: Design Doc To Prototype</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/09/Games-Design-Doc-To-Prototype.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Games: Design Doc To Prototype" /><published>2017-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/09/Games-Design-Doc-To-Prototype</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/09/Games-Design-Doc-To-Prototype.html">&lt;p&gt;Now here’s a question: How do you go, from a design document, to a playable
prototype?&lt;br /&gt;
..Because I certainly have no idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s my best guess – and if you stick around, and if you follow
this procedure, &lt;em&gt;and especially&lt;/em&gt; if you are goopy game dev like me, I
think you’ll find that this &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; adds some well deserved, disciplined methods of fruition.. to the upturned fruit basket that is our creative chaos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-1-break-the-game-flow-down-into-moments&quot;&gt;Step 1: Break the game flow down into moments.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are all of the unique interaction states the player can be in?
Is the player eating pellets and avoiding ghosts at the same time; or is
the player walking around, enjoying the scenery in one moment, and staring
at a grid, trying to solve a puzzle in another?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-2-outline-the-core-systems-needed-for-each-moment&quot;&gt;Step 2: Outline the core systems needed for each moment.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the key ingredients that not only allow this moment to work,
but really &lt;em&gt;define&lt;/em&gt; this moment? Is the player walking normally in
this moment, or is the way the player slides down that sand dune actually
significant?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-3-elaborate-on-the-needs-for-each-core-system-to-work-both-together-and-individually&quot;&gt;Step 3: Elaborate on the needs for each core system to work, both together and individually.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the actual controls for this moment? Is the camera moving on
its own, is it directly controlled by the player, or is it just influenced
by the player? What about the npc behaviors? Are they signficant? Do they
depend on what moment the player is currently experiencing? It’s hard to
really nail down this step, as actual iteration will be required to get
everything right. The actual important key here, is discovered in the
process of actually exploring and uncovering what needs are worth
elaborating on. The specifics of the elaborations are not as
significant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-4-given-these-core-systems-and-needs-suggest-methods-of-implementation&quot;&gt;Step 4: Given these core systems and needs, suggest methods of implementation.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What code/pre-existing knowledge can you re-use? This is the part that
requires further research. Given the new list of details you have now,
this part should be much easier. If you are still having a hard time, try
re-visiting the steps on problematic areas and further dissecting and
simplifying your ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="gamedev" /><summary type="html">Now here’s a question: How do you go, from a design document, to a playable prototype? ..Because I certainly have no idea.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">thatfeelchallenge</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/02/thatfeelchallenge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="thatfeelchallenge" /><published>2017-05-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/02/thatfeelchallenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/article/2017/05/02/thatfeelchallenge.html">&lt;p&gt;Do you ever get that feeling of fervor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are so harmonious, so in-tune, with your work, the hours slip by unnoticed? When you find your mind has curled on its own smile? And raw energy crawls out from the corners of your eyes, as the billowing nest within you can no longer contain your enthusiasm? And as your hand moves to complete that next bit of craft, you transcend humanity into the divinity, just for this one moment, just for the joy of your passions, and for the next moment, and the next.. and you never want to stop learning. And you never want to stop growing. And you are in joy with doing that which is naturally avoided, you are in joy with work. YOUR work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you ever get that feeling, that it might all go away?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’ve worked not just so hard, but so persistently,&lt;br /&gt;
to recover,&lt;br /&gt;
to recover that feeling I once had as a kid.&lt;br /&gt;
How does one reclaim, that sustainable fervor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not entirely sure how or why I stumbled onto &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jenovachen.com/flowingames/thesis.htm&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Jenova Chen’s thesis on flow&lt;/a&gt;, or why it resonated so strongly with me, so I’m not going to even bother elaborating. Just know that it’s super awesome and somehow brain-synced me into looking at game-design with a new and critical eye. More importantly, it nudged together the seedling threads of design through sense-feeling for me. And for that, I will be ever greatful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curious me I am, as I sit there, harumping through thatgamecompany’s job descriptions. I’ve never actually heard of a Feel Engineer before this, but after reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://thatgamecompany.com/company/jobs/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;what exactly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that entailed. I just knew.. oh, that’s me. That’s what feels most important to me. &lt;em&gt;That’s&lt;/em&gt; what I feel fervor for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;..Will I actually go on to work at thatgamecompany? &lt;em&gt;shrug&lt;/em&gt; Don’t know. That’s not what is important to me. What’s important is their sample test sounds like a blast. And one way or another, I’d very much like to get paid to have fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;thatgamecompany-sample-feel-engineer-test&quot;&gt;thatgamecompany sample feel engineer test&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Submit &lt;strong&gt;a 3D game prototype that uses interaction design and aesthetics to evoke in players a feeling&lt;/strong&gt; of hopefulness. The prototype should feature a central character (not necessarily a person) that navigates through a 3D space.&lt;br /&gt;
We’re looking for a demonstration of your technical abilities as well as your design sensibilities so &lt;strong&gt;focus on interactive design and moment-to-moment feedback&lt;/strong&gt; that best showcases your taste and skill set. We favor minimalist design, and would prefer to see &lt;strong&gt;a simple concept executed with a high level of polish and a sense of depth&lt;/strong&gt;. Include any additional elements (objects, player mechanics, sound, etc.) as you see fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve highlighted my focii in bold. I actually may end up veering towards a hopeful feeling as requested by the description, but it’s just the bare idea of evoking feeling through interaction and simple aesthetic that I find tantalizing. I’m eager to explore any and all emotion(s). But, I’ll hone it down just to one for this project. I’ll develop that more as I explore what the mechanics naturally apparate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in addition to that description, a handful of rules and regulations were stapled:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple favored factors,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We want to see:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Emotion through motion and interaction&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Technical wonder&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Depth of moment-to-moment feedback&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thoughtful, cohesive design choices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a couple stipends,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Limit reliance on:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Explicit narrative (characters, plot, objectives)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Detailed models, animations, or textures&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;World/level layout&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;..write your demo in C or C++ or Javascript/WebGL rather than using an off-the-shelf engine.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, everything I wanted to do. I’m in. This project will be done in C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;One last self imposed caveat, DEADLINE: END OF MAY&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="challenge" /><category term="gamefeel" /><summary type="html">Do you ever get that feeling of fervor?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SphereKoan #001</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/02/SphereKoan-001.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SphereKoan #001" /><published>2017-05-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/02/SphereKoan-001</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/devlog/2017/05/02/SphereKoan-001.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SphereKoan001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SphereKoan Design Doc&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent most of my time working with porting a different project of mine
today, but I managed to get a quick design doc out for the proto-type. You can
see the outline for this very blog post in there. :O!! Scandalous!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the topic of funnies, I actually had to look up how to even shade a
sphere, and spent a good couple of a couple of minutes working on that legendary
concept art on the left side. It’s very simple, but I feel oddly proud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything considered, I’m pretty happy with today’s progress. I have gotten
a lot of different kinds of work done. And Although admittedly not as much as
I’d like for this project in particular, I’m &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; pleasantly surprised
I managed to get out this first log at all, and with a proper intro too!
Ohohoho, no corner cutting here. -Harumph-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I will make sure to take note of balancing the time spent between my
projects. That fervor must be distributed! No greedies!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m i.i,&lt;br /&gt;
and okay bye&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devlog" /><category term="challenge" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello, World.</title><link href="https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2016/12/29/Hello-World.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello, World." /><published>2016-12-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2016/12/29/Hello-World</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyedoteye.github.io/notice/2016/12/29/Hello-World.html">&lt;p&gt;I am making blog. Look at me go. Woof Woof. I am dog now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bark.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notice" /><category term="informative" /><summary type="html">I am making blog. Look at me go. Woof Woof. I am dog now.</summary></entry></feed>